# Srivas Chennu

srivaschennu.github.io +44 7828 90 66 92 srivas@gmail.com



### **Profile**

Machine learning science team leader at Apple. Have developed ML models across multiple application domains. Led research team of scientists. 12+ years of post-PhD R&D experience spanning the UK (Cambridge), Germany and India. Research featured by the BBC, Wired Magazine, and New Scientist. Have consulted for multiple startups.

#### Research

Co-authored 50+ peer-reviewed publications in academic journals, cited nearly 3000 times. <a href="https://hindex.of.26">h-index.of.26</a> (as of 2022). Have published research on a wide range of topics including time series analysis, deep learning, reinforcement learning, Bayesian methods, graph network analysis and probabilistic inference.

### **Employment**

ML Science Team Leader Apple, UK

2019-present

Lead team building models for predicting and optimising user engagement across Apple's services. Helped improve user acquisition and retention, producing measurable increase in revenue. Co-led adoption of interpretable reinforcement learning. Co-developed Bayesian inference framework powering App Store's product page optimisation feature for AB testing. Published papers at KDD.

Assistant Professor, Team Leader

#### University of Kent, UK

2016-2019

Led health care AI research team of 4 scientists. Delivered software for measuring biomarkers of consciousness using time series modelling and network analysis, enabling improved bedside evaluation of patients. Secured independent research funding. Published papers in high-impact journals. Research featured in a BBC Panorama special *The Mind Reader: Unlocking My Voice.* 

Visiting Researcher

# The Alan Turing Institute, UK

2018

Developed ML models for automated diagnostics of brain states using EEG time series.

Senior Research Associate

#### University of Cambridge, UK

2010-2016

Developed spectral coherence methods and causal models of EEG time series for predicting conscious states during anaesthesia and after severe brain injury. Research profiled in the *BBC*, *New Scientist*, *Scientific American*, *Der Spiegel*, and *Wired*. Gave public at *Wellcome Collection* and *New Scientist Live*.

Graduate Research Assistant

### Fraunhofer Institute, Germany

2005

Worked on an EU-funded project on QoS-aware broadband internet using resilient optical access. networks.

Graduate Research Assistant

# Hamburg University of Technology, Germany

2005

Developed convex optimisation and linear programming solutions for industrial applications. Published an algorithmic methodology for decentralization of real-time control systems.

Member of Technical Staff

### **Oracle Corporation, India**

2002-2004

Worked as software engineer in the *Oracle Reports* team, a part of Oracle's *Internet Application Server* platform. Build internal QA tools in Java, C++ and shell scripts.

Project Trainee

### Indian Institute of Science, India

2002

Implemented algorithms and user interface for the display and manipulation of image formats.

Project Trainee

## Centre for AI and Robotics, India

2002

Designed and implemented a prototype network intrusion and anomaly detection system in C++.

#### **Consulting**

### DataTiger (Marketing optimisation start-up acquired by Apple)

2018

Applied ensemble machine learning for predicting customer retention in online multiplayer games. Built unsupervised learning models for personalising timing of marketing communications.

#### Rsrchxchange (FinTech start-up)

2017

Built neural network-based NLP model for content similarity analysis of financial research reports. Developed latent factor models with Apache Spark to build financial research recommender models.

#### **Education**

#### **PhD** in Computer Science

University of Kent, Canterbury, UK

2006-2009

Thesis title: *The temporal spotlight of attention: computational and electrophysiological explorations* (approved with no corrections)

**MSc in Information and Communication Systems** Hamburg University of Technology Hamburg, Germany

2004-2006

Overall ECTS grade: 1.3 (Very Good; Passed with Distinction)

**BEng in Computer Science and Engineering** 

Visveswaraiah Technological University

1998-2002

Bangalore, India

Overall percentage score - 81.46% (First Class with Distinction)

#### **Skills**

- Big Data Modelling, Cloud Computing on AWS
- Parametric, Non-parametric and Bayesian Statistics
- Signal Processing and Time Series Analysis
- Graph Theory and Network Analysis
- Tools: tensorflow, pytorch, pyro, scipy, pandas, pyspark
- Languages: Python, MATLAB, JAVA, C++, C

- Deep Neural Networks
- · Probabilistic Machine Learning
- Applied Artificial Intelligence
- Computer Networking and Security

#### **Selected Publications**

**Chennu**, Maher, Martin & Prabhanantham. 2022. <u>Dynamic Memory for Interpretable Sequential Optimisation</u>. *Workshop on Online and Adaptive Recommender Systems, ACM SIGKDD.* 

**Chennu**, Martin, Liyanagama & Mohr. 2021. <u>Smooth Sequential Optimisation with Delayed Feedback</u>. *Workshop on Bayesian Causal Inference in Real-World Interactive Systems, ACM SIGKDD*.

Patlatzoglou, Wolff, Gosseries, Bonhomme, Laureys & **Chennu**. 2020. <u>Generalized Prediction of Unconsciousness</u> <u>during Propofol Anesthesia using 3D Convolutional Neural Networks</u>. *The 42nd International Conference of the IEEE Engg. and Biology Society*.

**Chennu**, Annen, Wannez, Thibaut et al. 2017. <u>Brain networks predict metabolism, diagnosis and prognosis at the bedside in disorders of consciousness</u>. *Brain*, 140(8), 2120-2132.

**Chennu**, Finoia, Kamau, Allanson et al. 2014. <u>Spectral signatures of reorganised brain networks in disorders of consciousness</u>. *PLOS Computational Biology*, 10(10), e1003887